thinktechtips.com 2013-09-25

# Privacy - Think Tech Tips (TTT)

We are glad to welcome you to ThinkTechTips. Please read this privacy statement to ensure that we are committed to keeping secure the privacy of our members’ (customers) details. This privacy policy outlines important information regarding the use and disclosure of User information collected via the Website.

Think Tech Tips provides this privacy policy to help Users make an informed decision as to whether to use or continue using the website.

**Collected Information**

The information that we collect from the members using the site falls into the following general categories:

**1\. User provided data**  
Users may provide personally identifiable information (such as a name and an email address) to ThinkTechTips when choosing to participate in the various services available on the website, such as sharing views via comment or feedback or other content (collectively, the “Content”) for public viewing interests, entering contests, accessing promotions, responding to surveys or other personalized services (collectively, the “Services”).

**2\. Cookies**

When you visit ThinkTechTips.com, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. ThinkTechTips.com may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser help file directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the website may not function properly. Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to deliver the advertisements and links that appear on Think Tech Tips.com. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

ThinkTechTips.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. ThinkTechTips privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**3\. Clear / transparent GIFs information:**

ThinkTechTips.com may choose to utilize “clear .GIFs” to track the online usage patterns of our users in a non-personally identifiable manner. Additionally, ThinkTechTips.com may also use clear .GIFs in HTML-based emails dispatched to users so as to track which emails are being opened by the recipients. This act helps ThinkTechTips.com to determine active and inactive email addresses.

**4\. Log data file information:**

When users log-in to their ThinkTechTips.com account, our servers may automatically record and archive certain information that web-browsers send whenever visiting a website. These server logs may include information vital to validating the user’s authorization to access the account. Information, such as a web request, internet protocol (the “IP”) address, browser type, browser language, referring pages, exit pages and visited URLs, platform type, click counts, pages viewed and in what order, time spent, the date and time of the request, and other important data is necessary to validate and authorize a User’s entry and activity on the website.

**Use of information**

  * Personally identifiable information submitted by a user on ThinkTechTips.com is used to operate, maintain, and provide features, general and unique, of the website for the user’s use and pleasure.
  * All personal information, data, or content that you, the user, voluntarily disclose to the website public areas become available to other users and can be collected and used by others. Your email id, name is displayed to other users when you comment on some story. Any content that you submit (the “User Submission”) may be redistributed throughout the Internet and other media channels, and/or may be viewed by the general public through other means not controlled by Think Tech Tips.com
  * ThinkTechTips.com does use your personally identifiable and certain non-personally identifiable information, such as but not limited to, anonymous user usage data, browser type, cookies, IP addresses, click stream data, and the like, to improve the quality and use designs of the Website through analysis of this data and trends.
  * We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the ThinkTechTips.com; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, and contests.
  * The site may include links to other websites and provides access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we do not control. When you access another website or purchase third party products or services through the site, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting or the provider of such products or services.

**External Links, Content and Third-Party Advertising**

ThinkTechTips is not responsible for the content of external sites, nor are external sites to which links are provided herein necessarily endorsed by ThinkTechTip. Recommended Links and links to merchant affiliates are provided as additional resources for our visitors, and at the time of review seemed to be suitable. We cannot assure that all the links found on Think Tech Tips.com are safe to use, if you are experiencing any difficulties with such links please contact us at [webmaster@ThinkTechTips.com](mailto:webmaster@ThinkTechTips.com).

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

One of our third-party advertiser include Google.Google uses DART technology, use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to this site and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).
